{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Consider the following statements",
        "answers": {
          "a": "The distance between metacentre and centre of buoyancy.",
          "b": "The distance between centre of buoyancy and centre of gravity.",
          "c": "The distance between metacentre and centre of gravity",
          "d": "None of the above"
        },
        
        "correctAnswer": "c",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "A pitot static tube having coefficient of velocity 0.98, measures velocities of water in a pipe. The stagnation pressure recorded is 3 m and static pressure 2 m. The actual velocity in pipe is?",
        "answers": {
          "a": "4.341 m/s",
          "b": "4.429 m/s",
          "c": "zero",
          "d": "4.431 m/s"
        },
       
        "correctAnswer": "a",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "Bernoulliâ€™s equation is applied to?",
        "answers":{
          "a": "Pitot tube",
          "b": "Venturimeter",
          "c": "Orifice meter",
          "d": "All of three mentioned here"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "A pitot static tube is used to measure the velocity of water in a pipe. The stagnation pressure head is 6 m and static pressure head is 5 m. Calculate the velocity of flow assuming the coefficient of tube equal to 0.98.",
        "answers":{
          "a": "8.92 m/s",
          "b": "5.09 m/s",
          "c": "4.34 m/s",
          "d": "12.9 m/s"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"c",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },{
        "question": "A pitot static tube is used to measure the velocity of water in a pipe. The stagnation pressure head is 6 m and static pressure head is 5 m. Calculate the velocity of flow assuming the coefficient of tube equal to 0.98.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"8.92 m/s",
          "b":"5.09 m/s",
          "c": "4.34 m/s",
          "d": "12.9 m/s"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"c",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"In a pitot tube, the kinetic energy is converted into _________",
        "answers":{
          "a": "potential energy",
          "b": "total energy",
          "c": "pressure energy",
          "d":"internal energy"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"c",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"The lower end of the pitot tube is bet at an angle of ___________?",
        "answers":{
          "a": "120 degrees",
          "b": "360 degrees",
          "c":"90 degrees",
          "d":"45 degrees"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"c",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "The errors generated in the pitot tube due to the location are called __________",
        "answers":{
          "a":"position errors",
          "b": "normal errors",
          "c":"negligible errors",
          "d": "positive errors"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"When an aircraft is grounded, the pitot static tube is generally covered.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
        
      },{
        "question":"The pressure measured relative to vacuum is ______",
        "answers":{
          "a":"total pressure",
          "b":"static pressure",
          "c": "dynamic pressure",
          "d": "absolute pressure"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"d",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      }
    ]
  }